<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CASAT Wiki on CASATdocs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/</link><description>Recent content in CASAT Wiki on CASATdocs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Node Exporter on Remote Servers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/metrics/node_exporter_install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 15:19:06 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/metrics/node_exporter_install/</guid><description>Installing Node Exporter on remote servers for Prometheus data collection create folder for exporter apps sudo mkdir /usr/local/bin/metrics
sudo mkdir /etc/metrics
sudo useradd -rs /bin/false exporter
sudo chmod -R 777 /usr/local/bin/metrics
sudo chmod -R 777 /etc/metrics
sudo chown -R exporter:exporter /usr/local/bin/metrics
sudo chown -R exporter:exporter /etc/metrics
Install node_exporter curl -O -L https://github.com/prometheus/node_exporter/releases/download/v1.2.2/node_exporter-1.2.2.linux-amd64.tar.gz
tar xzvf node_exporter-*.*-amd64.tar.gz
sudo mv node_exporter-*.*-amd64 /usr/local/bin/node_exporter
create service sudo vim /etc/systemd/system/node_exporter.</description></item><item><title>New WordPress server</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/wordpress/new_lamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:18:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/wordpress/new_lamp/</guid><description>Setting up a LAMP server Installing Apache Installing MySql Installing PHP Configuring the LAMP server Configuring the MySql database Creating an Apache VirtualHost Installing WordPress Download and unpack WordPress WordPress config file Copying WordPress to its proper location Installing wp-cli This tutorial will walkthrough the process of installing Apache, MySql, and PHP on an Ubuntu 20.</description></item><item><title>Adding SSL certificate to Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/adding_ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/adding_ssl/</guid><description>How we have been installing SSL certificates on our Apache servers Obtain certificate using Certbot Adapted from the Certbot website
Update snapd sudo snap install core; sudo snap refresh core
Install Certbot app sudo snap install --classic certbot
Prepare the Certbot command sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot
If Apache is currently running, disable it so Certbot can use the port sudo systemctl stop apache2.</description></item><item><title>CASAT Zoom Accounts</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/casat_zoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/casat_zoom/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Robocopy Notes</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/windows/robocopy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/windows/robocopy/</guid><description>When moving large files or large amounts of files/folders across the network you should use the robocopy app. It will look something like this:
robocopy &amp;lt;Source&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Destination&amp;gt; [&amp;lt;File&amp;gt;[...]] [&amp;lt;Options&amp;gt;]
In practice it will look something like this
robocopy $NETWORK_PATH $NEW_NETWORK_PATH /e /zb /dcopy:t /copy:all /r:2 /w:5 /v /tee /LOG:$PATH_TO_LOG
List Only Flag
It&amp;rsquo;s strongly suggested to do a test run with a robocopy command first to make sure you get the intended results, especially when the command involves moving files across the network.</description></item><item><title>UNR Resources</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/unr_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/unr_resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Adding logins with Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/htpasswd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/htpasswd/</guid><description>This is referred to as Apache &amp;lsquo;Basic Auth&amp;rsquo;. Following these directions will add a username and password prompt to a website or specific webpage. Typically we use this to hide a &amp;lsquo;Dev&amp;rsquo; website so it can still be accessible but not open to the public.
Using htpasswd to generate users and passwords Install Dependencies Make sure you have Apache Extended Utilities installed sudo apt update
sudo apt install apache2-utils
Create first user with htpasswd sudo htpasswd -c /etc/apache2/htpasswd.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR VPN</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</guid><description>UNR has a VPN (Virtual Private Network) which allows for staff to access the university network from home or other &amp;lsquo;remote&amp;rsquo; locations. Please note that this access is only available on request and is not granted implicitly.
These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR VPN Instructions
NOTE
Prior to completing these steps, open the File Explorer app in Windows and check under the &amp;lsquo;This PC&amp;rsquo; section. If you can see any of the UNR Network drives; I:casat, or H:home you will need to &amp;lsquo;disconnect&amp;rsquo; from them and restart your computer prior to connecting to the VPN.</description></item><item><title>Promtail Installation</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/metrics/promtail_install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/metrics/promtail_install/</guid><description>Promtail is an app for transferring logs from one server to another. For our use we are transferring logs from our many different VPS to our centralized Loki server.
Installing Promtail Begin by downloading the promtail app and installing it
curl -O -L https://github.com/grafana/loki/releases/download/v2.3.0/promtail-linux-amd64.zip
sudo apt install unzip
unzip promtail-linux-amd64.zip
sudo mv promtail-linux-amd64 /usr/local/bin/promtail
make conf file Make a configuration file for Promtail
sudo vim /etc/metrics/promtail.</description></item><item><title>Zoom with your UNR NetID (SSO Login)</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</guid><description>These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR Zoom Access and Support
1. Download the Zoom app Use this link to go to the Zoom website and download the Zoom app if you do not already have it Chrome should automatically start the download, otherwise you may need to click on the link to start the download manually 2. Install the Zoom app Once the download has completed, click on the download at the bottom of the screen If you get a &amp;lsquo;security warning&amp;rsquo; window, you are ok to tell it to &amp;lsquo;Run&amp;rsquo; Once the installer has completed you will get a window with two options: &amp;lsquo;Join a Meeting&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Sign in&amp;rsquo; Select &amp;lsquo;Sign In&amp;rsquo; 3.</description></item><item><title>Migrating websites</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/wordpress/migration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/wordpress/migration/</guid><description>Copying the data Exporting the data Importing the data Updating the URL in the database Updating the URL with wp-cli Updating the URL with MySql When migrating a WordPress website from one server/VPS to another there are two things we need to make sure we capture; the MySql database and the wp-content folder. The instructions below will walkthrough copying both the MySql database and the wp-content folders from an existing WordPress installation to another &amp;lsquo;blank&amp;rsquo; WordPress installation on a different VPS.</description></item><item><title>New devices for remote workers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/new_computer_remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/new_computer_remote/</guid><description>If you are one of our &amp;lsquo;permanent&amp;rsquo; remote workers you will receive a laptop from us for work use at home. Our typical remote setup includes a laptop, monitor, keyboard and mouse (and dock if necessary), all of which will be sent to you. On a typical setup you would plug the monitor into the laptop which will allow you to use either the monitor or both the monitor and the laptop as screens, and then the mouse and keyboard into the laptop.</description></item><item><title>Updating PHP 7.2 > 7.4 on Ubuntu 18</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/php72_74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/php72_74/</guid><description>I have had problems getting PHP 7.2 to update to 7.4 on Ubuntu 18.04. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did to get it working.
Manually add PHP repository and check again sudo apt install software-properties-common
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ondrej/php
sudo apt update
sudo apt upgrade
Check PHP version again php -v
If PHP still shows 7.2 then 7.4 needs to be manually installed
Install PHP 7.4 sudo apt install php7.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR Remote Desktop</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</guid><description>The university has a Remote Desktop server that allows you to work on the University Network from anywhere with an internet connection. When using the Remote Desktop you will be working on another desktop on a remote computer that has access to the UNR Network. The regular &amp;lsquo;Virtual Desktop&amp;rsquo; will allow you to access files on the Network and use the typical office apps. The &amp;lsquo;DataWorks&amp;rsquo; desktop is also available for more specialized computing needs.</description></item></channel></rss>