<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CASAT Wiki on CASATdocs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/</link><description>Recent content in CASAT Wiki on CASATdocs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installing Node Exporter on Remote Servers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/metrics/node_exporter_install/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 15:19:06 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/metrics/node_exporter_install/</guid><description>create folder for exporter apps sudo mkdir /usr/local/bin/metrics sudo mkdir /etc/metrics sudo useradd -rs /bin/false exporter sudo chmod -R 777 /usr/local/bin/metrics sudo chmod -R 777 /etc/metrics sudo chown -R exporter:exporter /usr/local/bin/metrics sudo chown -R exporter:exporter /etc/metrics Install node_exporter curl -O -L https://github.com/prometheus/node_exporter/releases/download/v1.2.2/node_exporter-1.2.2.linux-amd64.tar.gz tar xzvf node_exporter-*.*-amd64.tar.gz sudo mv node_exporter-*.*-amd64 /usr/local/bin/node_exporter create service sudo vim /etc/systemd/system/node_exporter.service [Unit] Description=Node exporter for Prometheus After=network.target [Service] User=exporter Type=simple ExecStart=/usr/local/bin/node_exporter/node_exporter [Install] WantedBy=multi-user.</description></item><item><title>New WordPress server</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/wordpress/new_lamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 12:18:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/wordpress/new_lamp/</guid><description>Setting up a LAMP server Installing Apache Installing MySql Installing PHP Configuring the LAMP server Configuring the MySql database Creating an Apache VirtualHost Installing WordPress Download and unpack WordPress WordPress config file Copying WordPress to its proper location Installing wp-cli This tutorial will walkthrough the process of installing Apache, MySql, and PHP on an Ubuntu 20.</description></item><item><title>Adding SSL certificate to Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/adding_ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/adding_ssl/</guid><description>Adapted from the Certbot website
Obtain a certificate using Certbot The Certbot app recommends using the &amp;lsquo;snap&amp;rsquo; package manager for installation. First we&amp;rsquo;ll make sure Snapd is installed and updated to handle the Certbot app installation. We then install the app, confirm that the command is correctly &amp;lsquo;linked&amp;rsquo; and then we&amp;rsquo;ll request a certificate.
Update snapd sudo snap install core; sudo snap refresh core Install Certbot app sudo snap install --classic certbot Prepare the Certbot command sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot If Apache is currently running, disable it so Certbot can use the port sudo systemctl stop apache2.</description></item><item><title>Robocopy Notes</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/robocopy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/robocopy/</guid><description>When moving large files or large amounts of files/folders across the network you should use the robocopy app. It will look something like this:
robocopy &amp;lt;Source&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Destination&amp;gt; [&amp;lt;File&amp;gt;[...]] [&amp;lt;Options&amp;gt;] In practice it will look something like this
robocopy $NETWORK_PATH $NEW_NETWORK_PATH /e /zb /dcopy:t /copy:all /r:2 /w:5 /v /tee /LOG:$PATH_TO_LOG List Only Flag
It&amp;rsquo;s strongly suggested to do a test run with a robocopy command first to make sure you get the intended results, especially when the command involves moving files across the network.</description></item><item><title>Adding logins with Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/htpasswd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/htpasswd/</guid><description>Following these directions will add a username and password prompt to a website or specific webpage. Typically we use this to hide a &amp;lsquo;Dev&amp;rsquo; website so it can still be accessible but not open to the public.
Using htpasswd to generate users and passwords Install Dependencies Make sure you have Apache Extended Utilities installed sudo apt update sudo apt install apache2-utils Create first user with htpasswd sudo htpasswd -c /etc/apache2/htpasswd.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR VPN</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</guid><description>UNR has a VPN (Virtual Private Network) which allows for staff to access the university network from home or other &amp;lsquo;remote&amp;rsquo; locations. Please note that this access is only available on request and is not granted implicitly.
These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR VPN Instructions
NOTE
Prior to completing these steps, open the File Explorer app in Windows and check under the &amp;lsquo;This PC&amp;rsquo; section. If you can see any of the UNR Network drives; I:casat, or H:home you will need to &amp;lsquo;disconnect&amp;rsquo; from them and restart your computer prior to connecting to the VPN.</description></item><item><title>Promtail Installation</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/metrics/promtail_install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/metrics/promtail_install/</guid><description>Promtail is an app for transferring logs from one server to another. For our use we are transferring logs from our many different VPS to our centralized Loki server.
Installing Promtail Begin by downloading the promtail app and installing it
curl -O -L https://github.com/grafana/loki/releases/download/v2.3.0/promtail-linux-amd64.zip sudo apt install unzip unzip promtail-linux-amd64.zip sudo mv promtail-linux-amd64 /usr/local/bin/promtail make conf file Make a configuration file for Promtail</description></item><item><title>Zoom with your UNR NetID (SSO Login)</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</guid><description>These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR Zoom Access and Support
Using your NetId to login to Zoom on the web To use your UNR NetId Zoom login over the web you need to make sure you are using the specific UNR Zoom web portal. https://unr.zoom.us From there you can login with your UNR NetId Not seeing the UNR login screen?
In some cases browsers are not correctly interpreting the unr.</description></item><item><title>Migrating websites</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/wordpress/migration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/wordpress/migration/</guid><description>Copying the data Exporting the data Importing the data Updating the URL in the database Updating the URL with wp-cli Updating the URL with MySql When migrating a WordPress website from one server/VPS to another there are two things we need to make sure we capture; the MySql database and the wp-content folder. The instructions below will walkthrough copying both the MySql database and the wp-content folders from an existing WordPress installation to another &amp;lsquo;blank&amp;rsquo; WordPress installation on a different VPS.</description></item><item><title>Updating PHP 7.2 > 7.4 on Ubuntu 18</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/php72_74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/server_notes/php72_74/</guid><description>I have had problems getting PHP 7.2 to update to 7.4 on Ubuntu 18.04. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did to get it working.
Manually add PHP repository and check again sudo apt install software-properties-common sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ondrej/php sudo apt update sudo apt upgrade Check PHP version again php -v If PHP still shows 7.2 then 7.4 needs to be manually installed
Install PHP 7.4 sudo apt install php7.</description></item><item><title>Accessing CASAT email</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/email/</guid><description>Accessing @casat.org emails Reporting malicious messages Managing Gmail groups Accessing @unr.edu emails Users at CASAT will be issued two different email accounts, an @casat.org email address accessed though Gmail and assigned by CASAT, and an @unr.edu email address accessed through Outlook and assigned by UNR IT. The directions below are specific to our Gmail/Gsuite @casat.org accounts.
Accessing @casat.org emails Users at CASAT are issued @casat.</description></item><item><title>Accessing Office on personal computers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/officeathome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/officeathome/</guid><description>As a UNR employee we are granted access to the Microsoft Office suite through our NetId accounts. Using this login there are two ways to get access to the Microsoft Office apps on your personal devices, over the web or installed locally on a personal device.
Over the web You can use Office on any personal device over the web without having to install anything. Simply open a web browser and goto portal.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR Remote Desktop</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</guid><description>The university has a Remote Desktop server that allows you to work on the University Network from anywhere with an internet connection. When using the Remote Desktop you will be working on another desktop on a remote computer that has access to the UNR Network. The regular &amp;lsquo;Virtual Desktop&amp;rsquo; will allow you to access files on the Network and use the typical office apps. The &amp;lsquo;DataWorks&amp;rsquo; desktop is also available for more specialized computing needs.</description></item><item><title>Remote Workers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/remote/</guid><description>If you are one of our remote workers you will receive a laptop from us for work use at home. Our typical remote setup includes a laptop, monitor, keyboard and mouse (and dock if necessary), all of which will be sent to you. On a typical setup you would plug the monitor into the laptop which will allow you to use either the monitor or both the monitor and the laptop as screens, and then the mouse and keyboard into the laptop.</description></item></channel></rss>