<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CASAT Resources on CASATdocs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/</link><description>Recent content in CASAT Resources on CASATdocs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/getting_started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/getting_started/</guid><description>When first getting your equipment from CASAT there are a few things you should do.
Logging into the computer Campus computers Off-Campus Computers Logging into Email Logging into @casat.org Emails Logging into @unr.edu Emails Logging into Office Applications File Storage UNR Network Storage Box Cloud Storage Other services Logging into the computer Campus computers CASAT&amp;rsquo;s computers will come setup one of two ways depending on where you are permanently located.</description></item><item><title>CASAT email</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/email/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/email/</guid><description>Accessing @casat.org emails Reporting malicious messages Managing Gmail groups Accessing @unr.edu emails Users at CASAT will be issued two different email accounts, an @casat.org email address accessed though Gmail and assigned by CASAT, and an @unr.edu email address accessed through Outlook and assigned by UNR IT. The directions below are specific to our Gmail/Gsuite @casat.org accounts.
Accessing @casat.org emails Users at CASAT are issued @casat.</description></item><item><title>Remote Workers</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/remote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/casat_resources/remote/</guid><description>If you are one of our remote workers you will receive a laptop from us for work use at home. Our typical remote setup includes a laptop, monitor, keyboard and mouse (and dock if necessary), all of which will be sent to you. On a typical setup you would plug the monitor into the laptop which will allow you to use either the monitor or both the monitor and the laptop as screens, and then the mouse and keyboard into the laptop.</description></item></channel></rss>