<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UNR resources on &lt;strong>CASAT&lt;/strong>docs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/</link><description>Recent content in UNR resources on &lt;strong>CASAT&lt;/strong>docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UNR Resources</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/unr_resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/unr_resources/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR VPN</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/vpn/</guid><description>UNR has a VPN (Virtual Private Network) which allows for staff to access the university network from home or other &amp;lsquo;remote&amp;rsquo; locations. Please note that this access is only available on request and is not granted implicitly.
These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR VPN Instructions
NOTE
Prior to completing these steps, open the File Explorer app in Windows and check under the &amp;lsquo;This PC&amp;rsquo; section. If you can see any of the UNR Network drives; I:casat, or H:home you will need to &amp;lsquo;disconnect&amp;rsquo; from them and restart your computer prior to connecting to the VPN.</description></item><item><title>Zoom with your UNR NetID (SSO Login)</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/zoom/</guid><description>These instructions are an adaptation of: UNR Zoom Access and Support
1. Download the Zoom app Use this link to go to the Zoom website and download the Zoom app if you do not already have it Chrome should automatically start the download, otherwise you may need to click on the link to start the download manually 2. Install the Zoom app Once the download has completed, click on the download at the bottom of the screen If you get a &amp;lsquo;security warning&amp;rsquo; window, you are ok to tell it to &amp;lsquo;Run&amp;rsquo; Once the installer has completed you will get a window with two options: &amp;lsquo;Join a Meeting&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Sign in&amp;rsquo; Select &amp;lsquo;Sign In&amp;rsquo; 3.</description></item><item><title>Connecting to the UNR Remote Desktop</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/unr_resources/remote_desktop/</guid><description>The university has a Remote Desktop server that allows you to work on the University Network from anywhere with an internet connection. When using the Remote Desktop you will be working on another desktop on a remote computer that has access to the UNR Network. The regular &amp;lsquo;Virtual Desktop&amp;rsquo; will allow you to access files on the Network and use the typical office apps. The &amp;lsquo;DataWorks&amp;rsquo; desktop is also available for more specialized computing needs.</description></item></channel></rss>