<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Server Resources on &lt;strong>CASAT&lt;/strong>docs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/</link><description>Recent content in Server Resources on &lt;strong>CASAT&lt;/strong>docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding SSL certificate to Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/adding_ssl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/adding_ssl/</guid><description>How we have been installing SSL certificates on our Apache servers Obtain certificate using Certbot Adapted from the Certbot website
Update snapd sudo snap install core; sudo snap refresh core
Install Certbot app sudo snap install --classic certbot
Prepare the Certbot command sudo ln -s /snap/bin/certbot /usr/bin/certbot
If Apache is currently running, disable it so Certbot can use the port sudo systemctl stop apache2.</description></item><item><title>Adding logins with Apache</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/htpasswd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/htpasswd/</guid><description>This is referred to as Apache &amp;lsquo;Basic Auth&amp;rsquo;. Following these directions will add a username and password prompt to a website or specific webpage. Typically we use this to hide a &amp;lsquo;Dev&amp;rsquo; website so it can still be accessible but not open to the public.
Using htpasswd to generate users and passwords Install Dependencies Make sure you have Apache Extended Utilities installed sudo apt update
sudo apt install apache2-utils
Create first user with htpasswd sudo htpasswd -c /etc/apache2/htpasswd.</description></item><item><title>Updating PHP 7.2 > 7.4 on Ubuntu 18</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/php72_74/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_notes/server_notes/php72_74/</guid><description>I have had problems getting PHP 7.2 to update to 7.4 on Ubuntu 18.04. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did to get it working.
Manually add PHP repository and check again sudo apt install software-properties-common
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ondrej/php
sudo apt update
sudo apt upgrade
Check PHP version again php -v
If PHP still shows 7.2 then 7.4 needs to be manually installed
Install PHP 7.4 sudo apt install php7.</description></item></channel></rss>