<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Windows and Active Directory Notes on CASATdocs</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows and Active Directory Notes on CASATdocs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Robocopy Notes</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/robocopy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/robocopy/</guid><description>When moving large files or large amounts of files/folders across the network you should use the robocopy app. It will look something like this:
robocopy &amp;lt;Source&amp;gt; &amp;lt;Destination&amp;gt; [&amp;lt;File&amp;gt;[...]] [&amp;lt;Options&amp;gt;] In practice it will look something like this
robocopy $NETWORK_PATH $NEW_NETWORK_PATH /e /zb /dcopy:t /copy:all /r:2 /w:5 /v /tee /LOG:$PATH_TO_LOG List Only Flag
It&amp;rsquo;s strongly suggested to do a test run with a robocopy command first to make sure you get the intended results, especially when the command involves moving files across the network.</description></item><item><title>New computer setup</title><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/new_device/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/new_device/</guid><description>8/29/22
Installing and configuring Windows 10 for the University network (NO CM).
1. Bootdisk F12 to get to the BIOS screen Select the USB boot disk from the list of &amp;lsquo;Boot Device&amp;rsquo; options In the Windows install screen Select &amp;lsquo;Custom: install Windows only&amp;rsquo; Delete all existing drive partitions If the application isn&amp;rsquo;t seeing the disk drive it&amp;rsquo;s likely that RAID setting in BIOS needs to be turned off When all partitions are deleted select the &amp;lsquo;Unallocated space&amp;rsquo; and then select &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;apply&amp;rsquo; Wait for install process to complete, and then automatically restart After the restart work through the Windows prompts When prompted for &amp;lsquo;How would you like to set up?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/DigitalSig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wiki.casat.org/it_resources/windows/DigitalSig/</guid><description>##How to Create a digital signature for signiing out equipment. Click on Digital Signature Configure New Digital ID Create New Digital ID Save to Windows Certificate Store (You can save to file if you feel comfotable doiong so) Fill out your digital Signature Name: your Name Organizational Unit: CASAT Organization Name: University of Nevada, Reno Email Address: Your UNR email Region: US Key 2048 Use Digital ID for: Digital Signatures</description></item></channel></rss>